Contact

drandreacns@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/andrea-holecek-b5282410 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Acute Care Leadership

Andrea Holecek

VP / CNO at CHI Saint Joseph Health - London London, Kentucky

Summary

I am a seasoned healthcare executive with a background of leadership in not-for-profit health care settings. I have experience with strategic planning and operational responsibilities for a variety of departments and specialties within the acute care setting.

I spent 28 years with Bayhealth, a two-campus medical center located in Central Delaware. I started my career at the bedside on a med-surg unit, where I developed my skills as a clinician and as a front line leader. I pursed my BSN and transitioned to a charge nurse role in the IV therapy / Chemotherapy department and continued my academic journey by pursuing an MSN with a specialty focus in oncology. After receiving my MSN, I was promoted to a role as an Oncology CNS, where I had clinical oversight of a 28-bed medical-surgical oncology inpatient unit. I also had system-wide influence with several projects,

In 2014 I co-authored Bayhealth's Magnet Document, which earned a site visit and ultimately Magnet Designation. In the fall of 2014, I was promoted to Senior Director of Patient Care Services and Magnet Program Director. In my director role, I was afforded a once-in-a-career opportunity to be a clinical lead for the design, build, transition, and activation of a new health campus in Milford, Delaware.

Today I serve as Vice President of Patient Care Services and Chief Nursing Officer for Saint Joseph Health in London, Kentucky.

I hold Masters Degrees in both Nursing and Business Administration, and I have a Doctorate of Education in Innovation and Organizational Leadership. I am board-certified as a nurse executive and a Fellow of the American College of Healthcare Executives. I have provided numerous lectures at the local, state, and national levels on various topics. In 2018, I co-authored a book entitled, "The Nurse's Healthcare Ethics Committee Handbook: Use of Leadership,

Advocacy, and Empowerment to Develop a Nurse-Led Ethics Committee."

Experience

CHI Saint Joseph Health
VP / CNO
June 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months)
London, Kentucky

Bayhealth

13 years 8 months

Sr. Director of Patient Care Services / Magnet Program Director December 2014 - June 2019 (4 years 7 months)

Manager of Dialysis, Vascular Access, and Medical Infusion February 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 11 months)

Clinical Nurse Specialist November 2005 - February 2012 (6 years 4 months)

Education

Wilmington University

Doctor of Education (EdD), Organizational Leadership · (2007 - 2010)